

Profile

Passionate about designing user-centered solutions.

My mission is to understand user's needs and desires to create real value for the user.

Skills

UX methods

Design research User centered design Moodboard

Storyboard Persona

Wireframes and prototypes
Usability testing
Creativity methods

Graphic

Illustrator

XD

After Effects

Lightroom

Photoshop

Premiere Pro

Coding

Java

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Python

Languages

German English

Janine Bauer

UX Designer

Call +49 176 789 59 814 Web janine-bauer.com Mail janine.bauer@me.com
City Erlangen, Germany

Work experience

Siemens Healthineers, Working student UX design

09.2020 - Present, Erlangen

- sketched storyboards, created prototypes and prepared creative workshops
- designed conversational UI prototypes and framed user onbarding pattern

CodeCamp:N, Working student UX/UI design

10.2018 - 08.2019, Nürnberg

- created style guide with CI guidelines, drafted wireframes and prototypes
- implemented the corporate website from scratch with the Jekyll framework

ProLeit AG, Softwaredeveloper and tester

07.2015 - 01.2017 and 07. - 09.2017, Herzogenaurach

- conception and development of a new internal SDK in a scrum team
- · web developement and testing for batch tracking systems

08.2012 - 07.2015, Herzogenaurach

- completed my training as an IT specialist for applied technology
- programmed logic controllers, created UIs, fixed bugs and tested hotfixes

Education

Julius Maximilian University of Würzburg

03.2021 - present, Würzburg

Master of Science, Human Computer Interaction

University of Applied Sciences Ingolstadt

09.2017 - 03.2021, Ingolstadt

Bachelor of Science, User Experience Design

Metropolia University of Applied Technology

08.2019 - 12.2019, Helsinki (Finland)

Semester abroad, Information Technology

Experience abroad

Work and travel

01.2017 - 07.2017, New Zealand

Participated on World Wide Opportunities on Organic Farms (WWOOF)